Finding Aid for Creighton R. Coleman Papers 1941-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Creighton R. Coleman Papers 1941-1977
Coleman, Creighton R., 1912-
2.3 linear ft.
Assistant chief of the decartelization branch, economics division in the Office of Military Government for Germany (US), 1946-1948; later Republican state senator from Marshall, Calhoun County, Michigan, 1949-1956. Reports, correspondence, memoranda, and photographs concerning his work in Germany; also miscellaneous files detailing his activities in the state legislature.
85986 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Judge Creighton R. Coleman (donor no. 5436 ) and came to the library in different accessions 1973-1974 and 1985.
The collection is open for research.
Creighton R. Coleman was assistant chief of the decartelization branch, economics division in the Office of Military Government for Germany (US), 1946-1948; later Republican state senator from Marshall, Calhoun County, Michigan, 1949-1956.
The collection is arranged into the following series: Office of the Military Government for Germany (US) Economics Division, Decartelization Branch; State Senator's Files; Topical Files; and Photographs.
Subjects:
Antitrust law--Germany.; Calhoun County (Mich.); Economics.; Germany.; Germany (Territory under Allied occupation, 1945-1955: U.S. Zone). Office of Military Government.; Legislators--Michigan.; Marshall (Mich.); Michigan. Legislature.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Republican Party (Mich.); United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1953.; World War, 1939-1945.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Coleman, Creighton R., 1912-; Germany (Territory under Allied occupation, 1945-1955: U.S. Zone). Office of Military Government.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Office of the Military Government for Germany (US) Economics Division, Decartelization Branch
  - Program and aims of the decartelization branch (Box 1)
  - Report on German Cartels and Combines, 1946, 3 volumes (Box 1)
  - Activities of the former Bayer I.G. Farbenindustrie A.G. in the Pharmaceutical Industry (Box 1)
  - The German Coal Economy (Box 1)
  - Statistical Annex: Report of the Military Governor, August 1947 andSeptember 1947, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Comparative Reading in Basic U.S. Policy Directives on Germany, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Economic Data on Potsdam Germany, September 1947 (Box 1)
  - Statistical Annex: Report of the Military Governor, August 1947 and September 1947, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Comparative Reading in Basic U.S. Policy Directives on Germany, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Economic Data on Potsdam Germany (Box 1)
  - Comparative Federal Constitutions (Box 1)
  - Annexes to Decartelization: Report of, 1948 (Box 1)
  - The Private Limited Companies Act (G.m.b.H.), 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - The German Commercial Code of, May 10, 1897, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - International Cartel Law, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - The German Law on Joint Stock Companies and Joint Stock Companies en Commandie of, January 30, 1937, 3 volumes (Box 1)
  - Decartelization in the U.S. Zone of Germany (Box 2)
  - Activities of I.G. Farbenindustrie A.G., in the Nitrogen Industry (Box 2)
  - Activities of I.G. Farbenindustrie A.G. in the Oils Industry (Box 2)
  - Activities of I.G. Barbenindustrie A.G. in the Dyestuff Industry (Box 2)
  - Legislation Procedures-Basic Papers (Box 2)
  - Decartelization of fertilizer sales syndicates (Box 2)
  - Press file concerning work of decartelization branch (Box 2)
  - Kilgore Committee Investigation (Box 2)
  - Cartel Laws-German (Box 2)
  - Decartelization Law, No. 56 (Box 2)
  - Committee to Investigate Decartelization testimony, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1948 (Box 2)
  - Memoranda and directives, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Drafts of writings and speeches (Box 2)
  - Biographical data (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea (Box 2)
  - Deconcentration and decartelization in West Germany, 1945-1953 by J.F.J. Gillen (Box 2)
  - A problem paper on present and future United States policy toward Germany-prepared by Harold C. Deutsch, 1955 (Box 2)
  - The German White Paper-1940 (Box 2)
  - A Year of Potsdam; the German Economy since the surrender (Box 2)
  - Cookbook-"Operation Vittles" (Box 2)
  - Germany's Major Industrial Combines, May 10, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Recommendation (Box 2)
  - Invitation (Box 2)
- State Senator's Files, 1949-1956
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Speeches (Box 3)
  - Press releases (Box 3)
  - Miscellanea (Box 3)
- Topical Files
  - Biographical and personal (Box 3)
  - Judge Training Programs (Box 3)
  - Justice Department personnel miscellanea (Box 3)
  - Kellogg Community College Nursing Program (Box 3)
  - Kellogg Community College Beginnings (Box 3)
  - Highway Legislation (Box 3)
  - Michigan Judges Association/Michigan Association of Counties Council (efforts at cooperation) (Box 3)
  - Military Government personnel records (Box 3)
  - Notre Dame (Visiting Japanese judges from) (Box 3)
  - State Senate (newsletter) (Box 3)
- Photographs
  - Photos of meetings of the decartelization branch; also portrait and miscellaneous photos of meetings and ceremonial functions (Box 3)